Mss.B.F113 Mss.B.F113 Mss.B.F113
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to ----, [1779]; B F113; 4-1/2x11; [Fabroni, Giovanni Valentino Mattia, 1752-1822.]
    A.L. 3p. Draft. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Topics of the day: Lord Sandwich scandal and the affaire between Keppel and Palliser.
  - Memoranda, [1779?]; B F113; 10-3/4x5; [Fabroni, Giovanni Valentino Mattia, 1752-1822.]
    A.D. 7p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning chemistry, especially phosphorus, with references to Wilson, Higgins and Beccaria.
  - Letter to [Thomas]., B F113; 9x7-1/2; [Fabroni, Giovanni Valentino Mattia,1752-1822.]
    A.L. 2p. Draft. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Recalls their friendly conversations. Cannot receive him, due to difficulties.
  - Letter to [Jean Phillippe François] Deleuze, Paris, Feb. 3, 1823; B F113; 12x8; [Fabroni, Leopoldo Pelli
    L. 4p. Draft. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Letters to him over death of his father Thanks him for his letter of condolence. Will do an éloge on his father. Refers to Cuvier.
  - Letter to [Lodovico Ciccolini?], March 6, 1824; B F113; 9x4-1/4; [Fabroni, Leopoldo Pelli
    L. 1p. Draft. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning the Duchess of Devonshire's Visit.
  - Endorsement sheet for letters of Giovanni Fabroni, written from London., B F113; 12-1/2x9; [Fabroni, Leopoldo Pelli
    A.D. 1p. In Italian. 9see Fabroni papers.)
  - Letter to [Joseph Phillippe François Deleuze], July 3, 1824; B F113; 12x8; [Fabroni, Leopoldo Pelli?
    L. 2p. Draft. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Asks if he can make Raddi a member of the Institut.
  - Concerning the Napoleonic Academy., B F113; 9-3/4x7-3/4; [Fabroni?, Giovanni Valentino Mattia,1752-1822]
    D. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.)
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, Sept. 29, 1786; B F113; 7-1/4x7-3/4; [Fontana, Abbé Felice, 1730-1805.]
    Pavia, L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. Mutilated. (see Fabroni papers.) Wants him to Write.
  - Poem:, B F113; 6x4; [Gianni, Francesco, 1750-1822.]
    "Il Gabbo al Dritto. Sonetto." A.D. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.)
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, June 30, 1801; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/4; [Hervey, Frederick August, 4th earl Bristol, 1730-1803.]
    Naples, A.L. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Describes his underwriting an artist for sculpturing some items for him.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Pirenzo, B F113; 7-1/2x4-1/2; [Hervey, Frederick August, 4th earl Bristol, 1730-1803.]
    Rome, A.L. 5p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Friendly, social letter, contains current news.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, B F113; 7-1/2x4-3/4; [Hervey, Frederick August, 4th earl Bristol, 1730-1803.]
    A.L. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Friendly letter. Family news.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, B F113; 7-1/2 x4-3/4; [Hervey, Frederick August, 4th earl Bristol, 1730-1803.]
    Rome, Wednesday. A.L. 3p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning his visit and the fact that his tutor has been sent from England to him.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence., B F113; 7-1/2x4-1/2; [Hervey, Frederick August, 4th earl Bristol, 1730-1803.]
    A.L. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Comments on the war.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Jan. 25, 1801; B F113; 7-1/2x4-1/2; [Hervey, Frederick Augustus, 4th earl Bristol, 1730-1803.]
    Rome, A.L. 2p.and add. In French and latin. (see Fabroni papers.) Sympathy letter. Current events.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, March 11, 1801; B F113; 7-1/2x5; [Hervey, Frederick Augustus, 4th earl Bristol, 1730-1803]
    A.L. 3p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) News of Europe and France. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, May 30, 1801; B F113; 7-1/2x 4-1/2; [Hervey, Frederick Augustus, 4th earl Bristol, 1730-1803]
    Rome, L. 3p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Current events.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, April 7, 1777-1779; B F113; 7-1/2x5; [Hervey, Frederick Augustus, 4th Earl, 1730-1803.]
    A.L. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Is to travel in Italy and wishes him to join them.
  - Letter to Monseigneur l'archevique de Toulouse., B F113; 8-1/2x6-3/4; [La Blancherie, Flammès Claude Catherine Pahin Champlain de, 1752-1811.]
    L. 3p. In French. Copy. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning his freedom for experiments in science.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Feb. 11, 1800?; B F113; 9x7-1/4; [Laplace?, Pierre Simon, marquis de, 1749-1827]
    L. 2p.and add. In Italina. (see Fabroni papers.) Refers to Lacepede.
  - Manuscript leaf., B F113; 11-1/2x8; [Maffei, Francesco Scipione, Marchese, 1679-1755.]
    A.D. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.)
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, April 11, 1808; B F113.m; 10x7-3/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning a "third term" for Jefferson and inserts part of his letter to Jefferson.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, April 15, 1808; B F113.m; 9x7; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo. 1p.and add. In Italian (see Fabroni papers.) Friendly note.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, April 20, 1808; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-3/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    A.L. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning agriculture.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, April 27, 1808; B F113.m; 9-1/2x7-1/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Friendly letter. Political events.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, May 9, 1808; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Needs money.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], May 27, 1808; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks for his favors. Repays money. Politics.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, June 6, 1808; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Botany. Slander in Paris. Politics.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, June 10, 1808; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Political theories.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, July 6, 1808; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Recommendation for political appointment.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, July 9, 1808; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    A.L. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, July 18, 1808; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Sympathetic letter for troubles.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, July 20, 1808; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Family difficulties.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Aug. 5, 1808; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Illness in the family.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Aug. 7, [1808]; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Illness of Teresa.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Aug. 22, 1808; B F113.m; 9-1/2x7-1/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo. 1p.and add. In Italian (see Fabroni papers.) Friendly letter. Family news.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Aug. 26, 1808; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning a supplication made to his imperial majesty [Napoleon?] about taxes.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Aug. 27, 1808; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo. 2p.and add. In Italian (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning taxes.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Aug. 29, 1808; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo. 1p.and add. In Italian (see Fabroni papers.) Business of taxes.
  - Letter to John [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Jan. 29, 1781; B F113.m; 9-1/2x7-1/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Friendly letter. Introduces Mr. Angelo Mezzeri, who carries this letter.
  - Letter to John [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Feb. 24, 1781; B F113.m; 9-1/2x7-1/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Genoa, A.L.S.: Pippo. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning his wife and their difficulties.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, March 7, 1781; B F113.m; 9-1/2x7; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Tells him he must write Jefferson, or woe unto him upon his [Mazzei's] return.
  - Letter to John Fabbroni [sic], March 15, 16, 1781; B F113.m; 9-1/2x7-1/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Quotes a letter from Adams. Refers to Jefferson.
  - Letter to John Fabbroni [Giovanni Fabroni], Florence, March 26, 1781; B F113.m; 10x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Leghorn, A.L.S.: Pippo. 2p.and add. In Italian (see Fabroni papers.) Business. Concerning his wife.
  - Letter to John Fabbroni [Giovanni Fabroni], Florence, April 27, 1781; B F113.m; 9-1/2x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Leghorn, A.L. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Asks that he help in some personal business. Concerning his wife.
  - Letter to John Fabbroni [Giovanni Fabroni], Florence, July 25, 1781; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-3/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning his wife.
  - Letter to John Fabbroni [Giovanni Fabroni], Florence, Aug. 3, 1781; B F113.m; 8-3/4x6; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Hopes to repay him what is owed, which was used by his wife.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Dec. 31, 1794; B F113.m; 10x7-3/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Botany.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, March 23, 1796; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Botany.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, April 7, 1796; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 1p.and add.,end. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Botany.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, April 8, 1796; B F113.m; 10x7-3/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Botanical matters. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], May 9, 1796; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 2p. In Italian (see Fabroni papers.) Botany. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Oct. 5, 1796; B F113.m; 7-1/2x5; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano, 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers) Has not written for he must copy what Jefferson has written him on the political situation of the U.S. Botany.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Oct. 10, 1796; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Transcribes (in English) letter of Jefferson concerning intemal affairs of U.S. He also requests seed of the winter vetch.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Oct. 17, 1796; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Wants answer to his letter so he can write Jefferson.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Oct. 28, 1796; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning Jefferson, his health and the U.S. Botany.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Nov. 12, 1796; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Lucca, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Dangers for the U.S. Concerning Jefferson and the U.S.
  - Letter to Nanni Fabbroni [Giovanni Fabroni], Florence, March 3, 1797; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Botany. Concerning the growing of pumpkin. Flowers.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], March 27, 1797; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 1p. In Italian (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning a loan. Botanical matters.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, April 12, 1797; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 1p.and add., end. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning a mutual acquaintance, Losi.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, April 26, 1797; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) French Revolution reaction in U.S. Refers to Jefferson.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, May 8, 1797; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning financial matters of Losi.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, May 15, 1797; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning Losi. Botany.
  - Letter to Nanni Fabbroni [Giovanni Fabroni], Florence, Aug. 11, 1797; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 4p.,add.,end. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning Jefferson's Notes on Virginia.
  - Letter to Nanni Fabbroni [Giovanni Fabroni], Florence, Aug. 14, 1797; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/4, 7-1/4x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 3p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Sent seeds to Jefferson. Wants his opinion of Jefferson's Notes on Virginia.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Oct. 6, 1797; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/4 and 5x8-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo. 5p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Botany. Concerning the growth of fruit trees. Floriculture.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Oct. 30, 1797; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 4p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers) Botany. Quotes part of his letter to the Marchese Manfredini. Floriculture.
  - Letter to Nanni Fabbroni [Giovanni Fabroni], Nov. 24, 1797; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolani. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Illness of Teresa. Botany. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, [1797?]; B F113.m; 9-1/2x7-1/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    A.L. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning a letter of Jefferson with reference to Pitt and Burke.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Jan. 22, 1798; B F113.m; 9-1/2x7-1/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Condolences on Teresa.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Sept. 10, 1798; B F113.m; 9-1/2x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 2p. In Italian (see Fabroni papers.) Travel to Paris. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Jan. 20, 1800; B F113.m; 8-3/4x7-1/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Prince Czartoryski.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Feb. 25, 1803; B F113.m; 8-1/4x6; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning his work on economics.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, March 5, 1803; B F113.m; 9-1/2x7-1/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Discusses Fabroni's "floating bricks" and hopes he will write Jefferson about them and send sample of earth used to make them. Wants publications for self and Jefferson.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Florence, March 14, 1803; B F113.m; 9-1/4x7-1/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers) Concerning his publication. Scientific news.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, March 18, 1803; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Talked with Englishman and American about his "floating brick". American is sure Congress has funds for useful inventions.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, March 25, 1803; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning finances.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, March 30, 1803; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-3/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Inquires as to the health of his wife. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], April 18, 1803; B F113.m; 9-1/2x8; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, May, 1803; B F113.m; 9-1/2x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    A.L. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Adds name and amount to list.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], July 6, 1803; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo, 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning Jefferson and quotes a translation he made referring to Indians. Concerning Appleton.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Nov. 16, 1803; B F113.m; 10x8; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers) Friendly letter. Botany.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Dec. 2, 1803; B F113.m; 10x8; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    A.L.S.: Pippo. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Botany.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Feb. 15, 1804; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-3/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning his scientific Russian correspondence. Concerning Italian scientific societies.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, March 7, 1804; B F113.m; 9-1/2x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Business. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, March 23, 1804; B F113.m; 9-1/2x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning Potocki.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, March 26, 1804; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Illness of Signora Teresa.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, April 4, 1804; B F113.m; 9-1/2x7; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning the poverty of Lopez.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, April 13, 1804; B F113.m; 9-1/2x7; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers) Concerning Lopez. Inquires of Signora Teresa. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], April 20, 1804; B F113.m; 9-1/2x7-1/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Friendly letter. Concerning Lopez, Valentino Feronda, etc.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, April, 1804; B F113.m; 10x6-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    A.L. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Writes hurridly, stating that the lawyer will carry things.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], July 30, [1804]; B F113.m; 10x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    A.L.S.: Pippo. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Received the book today.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Aug. 1, [1804]; B F113.m; 8-1/2x6; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    A.L.S.: Pippo. 1p.and add. In Italian (see Fabroni papers.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Aug. 6, 1804; B F113.m; 10x8; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo. 1p.and add. In Italian (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning his publication.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Aug. 24, 1804; B F113.m; 9-3/4x7-3/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning a young Italian who is emigrating to America. Refers to Jefferson.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Sept. 7, 1804; B F113.m; 9-1/2x7-1/4; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Wishes he could go to America with the young emigrant. Expects to return later. Refers to Jefferson, Adams, and Madison.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Sept. 10, 1804; B F113.m; 9-1/4x7; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo. 1p.and add. In Italian (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning his book.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Sept. 19, 1804; B F113.m; 9-1/4x7; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo. 1p.and add.,end. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers) Concerning his book. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, Oct. 15, 1804; B F113.m; 9-1/4x7; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning travelling. Friendly letter Attached with letter of same to same; April 29, 1805.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Dec. 31, 1804; B F113.m; 8x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) His book on Peru and Mexico. Direction for forwarding copies.
  - Letter to Nanni [Giovanni Fabroni], Oct., 1804; B F113.m; 10x7-1/2; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Sends report of a clash between the Americans and Barbary pirates.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Jan. 2, 1805; B F113.m; 9-1/2x7; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Conditions at "Cordone".
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], April 16, 1805; B F113.m; 9-1/2x7; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo Ortolano. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Friendly letter. Concerning America.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, April 29, 1805; B F113.m; 9-1/4x7; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]
    Pisa, A.L.S.: Pippo. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Friendly letter. Attached to this letter is letter of same to same; Oct. 15, 1804.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni [sic], Florence, May 27, 1805; B F113.m; 9-1/4x7; [Mazzei, Filippo, 1730-1816.]